<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Memoria Applications on</title><link>https://memoria-framework.dev/docs/applications/</link><description>Recent content in Memoria Applications on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 08:48:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://memoria-framework.dev/docs/applications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hybrid AI</title><link>https://memoria-framework.dev/docs/applications/aiml/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memoria-framework.dev/docs/applications/aiml/</guid><description>What is &amp;ldquo;Hybrid AI&amp;rdquo; in Memoria? Historically, by Hybrid AI people meant something related to Khaneman&amp;rsquo;s Dual process theory or any combination of &amp;ldquo;intuitive reasoning&amp;rdquo; (shallow, fast and wide System 1) and &amp;ldquo;symbolic reasoning&amp;rdquo; (deep, slow and narrow System 2) that are expected to complement each other. LLMs turned out to be well-hybridizable with many different technologies, not limited to symbolic reasoners and databases. So, interests in ANNs is fueling secondary interest in technologies that previously have been resting in an oblivion.</description></item><item><title>Computational Storage</title><link>https://memoria-framework.dev/docs/applications/storage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memoria-framework.dev/docs/applications/storage/</guid><description>Basic Information Computational storage device or CSD is a computer device which primary function is data storage, but that can also perform certain data processing functions. Functions can be either pre-configured or user-provided, both offline and online.
There are two main reasons one may need a CSD.
It can significantly reduce computational system design complexity by eliminating dependency from CPU and operating system. CSD may perform all essential storage functions like object space management, concurrency and transactions on-device.</description></item><item><title>Converged Databases</title><link>https://memoria-framework.dev/docs/applications/db/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memoria-framework.dev/docs/applications/db/</guid><description>Database = storage + type system.
The problem is that storage and type system must be co-designed. In regular programming we rely on the composability principle for build our solutions out of reusable building blocks that can be designed independently. Databases are very different: data structures (containers in Memoria), in general, are not composable under concurrent updates. We need transactions. Implementing transactions is tricky, we probably need to do it on a per-container basis (one way for tables, another way for indices, blobs, graphs, etc&amp;hellip;)</description></item><item><title>HW/SW Co-design</title><link>https://memoria-framework.dev/docs/applications/co-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memoria-framework.dev/docs/applications/co-design/</guid><description>This page describes functionality or feature that may not necessary exist at the time of writing. HW/SW co-design is meant to be a showcase of Memoria as an application development framework, it will be gradually available when it&amp;rsquo;s ready.
Basic information By hardware/software co-design we mean a system design process when, given some functionality, we have a choice to implement it in hardware or in software. Actually, there are not that much of substantial difference between those two options, the problem is that corresponding engineering practices are very different.</description></item><item><title>Embedded and IoT Applications</title><link>https://memoria-framework.dev/docs/applications/eiot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memoria-framework.dev/docs/applications/eiot/</guid><description>Current Status Memoria is a pretty heavyweight framework and most likely isn&amp;rsquo;t suitable for embedded and IoT applications running on micro-controllers with little memory onboard. Some parts of the framework, like lightweight Hermes profiles can be scaled down to such MCUs and used for data storage and communication purposes.
Another limitation, that is not fundamental, is that Memoria assumes 64-bit hardware. Compiling it for 32-bit hardware is possible, but ensuring that everything works correctly and there are no performance regressions is not currently a priority.</description></item></channel></rss>